

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have 4+ years in Frontend software development and developed a variety of projects for various clients as listed on my CV. My programming experience is based on Object Oriented Languages and i use frameworks such as React, Python(fastAPI), Golang and Yii2 frameworks in PHP for software development to use the latest security and project structure features provided by the frameworks. I have intermediate experience in Devops having deployed Hela Pesa website and extensive experience in frontend frameworks such JQuery, Bootstrap, Html5, CSS3 and ReactJS. I have extensive experience in API development, System Security, Server administration and System Scaling (using kubernetes). Having worked and managed different projects, I believe I am quite adaptable to different situations and project requirements. I use git version control to track changes and work as part of a team.

Fun fact: What three words best describe you?

Creative, Problem Solver, Passionate

#### Skills, Tools and Specializations Technical skills

These skills cover languages, frameworks, libraries, and technical stacks.

| Agile<br>Expert, 3 yrsReact.js<br>Expert, 3 yrsRedux<br>Expert, 3 yrsRedux Material-UI<br>Expert, 3 yrsResponsive Web Design<br>Expert, 3 yrsExpert, 3 yrsExpert, 3 yrsExpert, 3 yrsExpert, 3 yrs |               |               |               |                   |                       |
|---|---------------|---------------|---------------|-------------------|-----------------------|
| Expert, 3 yrs   | Agile         | React.js      | Redux         | Redux Material-UI | Responsive Web Design |
|   | Expert, 3 yrs | Expert, 3 yrs | Expert, 3 yrs | Expert, 3 yrs     | Expert, 3 yrs         |

## Tools, utilities and services

Tools are third-party websites, SAAS products, and support services used during the course of software development.

Git Expert, 4 yrs

#### Specializations

Specializations are particular areas in which a developer is able to concentrate on and/or become an expert in.

DevOps Intermediate, 2 yrs

## WORK HISTORY

### Nairobi, Nairobi

**Graphine East Africa Limited** 

### Feb 2019 - Current · 3 yrs

Biotechnology, Computer Software [SaaS],

Education/EdTech, Information Technology & Services,

eCommerce Industry

51-200 employees

### - Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software. -

Front-end Software Developer (Full time)

Communicating technical issues in an understandable manner to the team and clients. - Develop new user-facing features - Tailoring user experience - Production, modification, and maintenance of websites and web application user interfaces -Designing and implementing responsive design for mobile sites - Contributing some back-end experience, collaborating on APIs tailoring - Maintaining software workflow management with Git and GitHub - Carrying out Automatic deployment -Mentoring teams

## Accomplishments

- Implementing web design and development
- Communicating technical issues in an understandable manner to the team and clients.
- Contributing some back-end experience, collaborating on APIs tailoring
- Maintaining software workflow management with Git and GitHub
- Mentoring teams on the importance of check

- Carrying out Automatic deployment

## Nairobi, Kenya

## May 2020 - Aug 2020 · 5 mo

Hela Pesa

Financial Services

11-50 employees

## Fande Data Systems Company

# Nairobi, Kenya

Oct 2018 - Jul 2019 · 10 mo Computer Software [SaaS], Financial Services,

Outsourcing/Offshoring, eCommerce Industry

Flexpay Limited

Sep 2016 - Oct 2018 · 2 yrs

eCommerce Industry

51-200 employees

Nairobi, Kenya

11-50 employees

# Worked as Devops Engineer

Devops Engineer (Part time)

Accomplishments

## Used CI/CD pipelines to carry out automatic deployments

#### React.js, Redux, TypeScript, jQuery, ES6. - Creating Servers and REST APIs using Golang, PHP - Setting up, Developing and Maintaining Databases: MySQL, Postgres.

Software Developer (Contract)

Accomplishments

Designing mockups and developing Websites

Creating Servers and REST APIs using Golang, PHP

 Setting up, Developing and Maintaining Databases: MySQL, Postgres. Devops: Docker

- Designing mockups and developing Websites - Frontend Development using

- Devops: Docker - Shipping code in a team environment - Testing to identify bugs

and technical issues before and after deploying. - Documenting bug reports, tickets,

Shipping code in a team environment

and any code changes.

Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying.

Junior Software Developer (Full time)

Documenting bug reports, tickets, and any code changes.

 Development of new software products - Bringing mockups to life using HTML, CSS, JavaScript. - Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable. -Maintenance of existing software products - Development of web application backend with PHP/Yii - Code version control using Git VCS and GitHub

# Development of new software products

Accomplishments

- Bringing mockups to life using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable.
- Maintenance of existing software products
- Development of web application backend with PHP/Yii Code version control using Git VCS and GitHub

# Huawei

**EDUCATION & LEARNING** 

May 2020 - Jun 2021 · 1.1 yrs

Nairobi, Kenya

Nairobi, Kenya

Jan 2017 - Jan 2021 · 4 yrs

Technical University of Kenya

Nakuru, Kenya

Kieni Secondary School

Jan 2013 - Jan 2016 · 3 yrs

Acquired various skills in networking - TCP/IP - VRP - Ethernet Switching - IP Unicast Routing - IP Service - Advanced switching technologies - Introduction to - WAN - Access Control - Network Management

# Graduated with a diploma certificate in computer technology

Diploma in Computer Technology

Certificate in Routing and Switching

Certificate in Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Quickfix

Attained certificate of K.C.S.E.

#### Quickfix Feb 2019 - Nov 2021 · 3 yrs

TECHNICAL PROJECTS



Communicating technical issues in an understandable manner to the team and clients. - Develop new user-facing features - Tailoring user experience - Production, modification, and maintenance of websites and web application user interfaces -Designing and implementing responsive design for mobile sites - Contributing some back-end experience, collaborating on APIs tailoring - Maintaining software workflow management with Git and GitHub - Carrying out Automatic deployment -Mentoring teams on the importance of checking the website for cross-browser compatibility issues. Redux Material-UI React.Js Git Redux

- Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software. -



Topratedprofessors - Designing mockups and developing Websites - Frontend Development using React.js, Redux, TypeScript, jQuery, ES6. - Creating Servers and REST APIs using

Golang, PHP - Setting up, Developing and Maintaining Databases: MySQL, Postgres. - Devops: Docker - Shipping code in a team environment - Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying. - Documenting bug reports, tickets, and any code changes. Git React.Js

Redux

DevOps

Topratedprofessors

Jan 2018 - Dec 2019 · 2 yrs